<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>apps on jamesm.blog</title>
    <link>https://jamesm.blog/tags/apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in apps on jamesm.blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 09:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamesm.blog/tags/apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Music Production: Mobile Apps</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/mobile-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/mobile-apps/</guid>
      <description>iPad &amp;amp; iPhone Apps Recommended iPad &amp;amp; iPhone apps &amp;hellip;
Ableton Ableton Note - A place to start musical ideas KORG ARP ODYSSEi - The ARP Odyssey of 1972 has earned an unshakable position as a classic analog synthesizer. In 2015, KORG produced the ARP ODYSSEY, a complete reproduction of the original KORG ELECTRIBE Wave - Groovebox KORG Gadget 3 - A Complete, Seamlessly Integrated Music Production Ecosystem KORG iMono/Poly - Synthesizer / Keyboard KORG iWAVESTATION - Synthesizer KORG Module Pro - High resolution Piano/Keyboard Modartt Pianoteq 8 - Pianoteq is an award-winning virtual instrument that can simulate many instruments (Pianos, Electric Pianos, Harpsichords, Vibraphones, Guitar, Steeldrums and more) thanks to physical modelling Roland Roland Zenbeats - Roland Zenbeats is a music creation app that keeps you in an effortless artistic flow.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="ipad--iphone-apps">iPad &amp; iPhone Apps</h1>
<p>Recommended iPad &amp; iPhone apps &hellip;</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/developer/ableton-ag/id1228664884">Ableton</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/ableton-note/id1633243177">Ableton Note</a> - A place to start musical ideas</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/developer/korg-inc/id363714046">KORG</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/arp-odyssei/id1147432809">ARP ODYSSEi</a> - The ARP Odyssey of 1972 has earned an unshakable position as a classic analog synthesizer. In 2015, KORG produced the ARP ODYSSEY, a complete reproduction of the original</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/korg-electribe-wave/id1399464596">KORG ELECTRIBE Wave</a> - Groovebox</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/korg-gadget-3/id791077159">KORG Gadget 3</a> - A Complete, Seamlessly Integrated Music Production Ecosystem</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/developer/korg-inc/id363714046">KORG iMono/Poly</a> - Synthesizer / Keyboard</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/korg-iwavestation/id1118072618">KORG iWAVESTATION</a> - Synthesizer</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/korg-module-pro/id932191687">KORG Module Pro</a> - High resolution Piano/Keyboard</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/developer/modartt/id1363148724">Modartt</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/pianoteq-8/id1642344241">Pianoteq 8</a> - Pianoteq is an award-winning virtual instrument that can simulate many instruments (Pianos, Electric Pianos, Harpsichords, Vibraphones, Guitar, Steeldrums and more) thanks to physical modelling</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/developer/roland-corporation/id387333694">Roland</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/roland-zenbeats/id1473380367">Roland Zenbeats</a> - Roland Zenbeats is a music creation app that keeps you in an effortless artistic flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/developer/sincere-apps/id1317949625">Sincere Apps</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/piano-chords-and-scales/id714086944">Piano Chords and Scales</a> - Play, learn theory, make songs</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="iphone-apps">iPhone Apps</h1>
<p>Recommended iPhone apps &hellip;</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/developer/korg-inc/id363714046">KORG</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/korg-ielectribe-for-iphone/id1006939067">KORG iELECTRIBE for iPhone</a> - The ELECTRIBE reborn in an even smaller form A full-fledged rhythm machine for iPhone</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI release ChatGPT app (iOS)</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/ai/chatgpt-app-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 19:05:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/ai/chatgpt-app-ios/</guid>
      <description>OpenAI have just released a new ChatGPT app which syncs your conversations, supports voice input, and brings our latest model improvements to your fingertips.
Download on the App Store The ChatGPT app is free to use and syncs your history across devices. It also integrates Whisper, an open-source speech-recognition system, enabling voice input. ChatGPT Plus subscribers get exclusive access to GPT-4’s capabilities, early access to features and faster response times, all on iOS.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI have just released a new ChatGPT app which syncs your conversations, supports voice input, and brings our latest model improvements to your fingertips.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/openai-chatgpt/id6448311069">Download on the App Store</a></li>
</ul>
<p>The ChatGPT app is free to use and syncs your history across devices. It also integrates Whisper, an open-source speech-recognition system, enabling voice input. ChatGPT Plus subscribers get exclusive access to GPT-4’s capabilities, early access to features and faster response times, all on iOS.</p>
<p>Discover the versatility of ChatGPT:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Instant Answers:</strong> Get precise information without sifting through ads or multiple results.</li>
<li><strong>Tailored Advice:</strong> Seek guidance on cooking, travel plans, or crafting thoughtful messages.</li>
<li><strong>Creative Inspiration:</strong> Generate gift ideas, outline presentations, or write the perfect poem.</li>
<li><strong>Professional Input:</strong> Boost productivity with idea feedback, note summarization, and technical topic assistance.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Opportunities:</strong> Explore new languages, modern history, and more at your own pace.</li>
</ul>
<p><em>Note</em>: Android app coming soon</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
