<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Yahama Montage M8X on jamesm.blog</title>
    <link>https://jamesm.blog/tags/yahama-montage-m8x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yahama Montage M8X on jamesm.blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 08:29:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamesm.blog/tags/yahama-montage-m8x/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yamaha Montage M</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/yamaha-montage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 08:29:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/yamaha-montage/</guid>
      <description>About The Yamaha Montage M was released in the UK on 10th October 2023.
It is the next-generation flagship synthesizer from Yamaha, building on the success of the original Montage. It boasts several improvements and new features designed to enhance the sound, control, and workflow for professional keyboardists.
Here is a summary of the key aspects of the Yamaha Montage M
Three Powerful Engines - Like its predecessor, Montage M features three sound engines: AN-X, AWM2, and FM-X.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/Yamaha-Montage-M.jpg" type="" alt="alt"  /></p>
<h2 id="about">About</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://uk.yamaha.com/en/products/music_production/synthesizers/montagem/index.html">Yamaha Montage M</a> was released in the UK on 10th October 2023.</p>
<p>It is the next-generation <strong>flagship synthesizer</strong> from Yamaha, building on the success of the original Montage. It boasts several improvements and new features designed to enhance the sound, control, and workflow for professional keyboardists.</p>
<p>Here is a summary of the key aspects of the Yamaha Montage M</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Three Powerful Engines</strong> -  Like its predecessor, Montage M features three sound engines: AN-X, AWM2, and FM-X. These engines offer a vast sonic palette, allowing you to create warm vintage analog tones, cutting-edge FM sounds, and ultra-realistic acoustic instruments.</li>
<li><strong>Increased Polyphony</strong> - A significant upgrade is the 400-note total polyphony, a jump from the original Montage&rsquo;s 256 notes. This allows for more complex and layered sounds without worrying about dropped notes.</li>
<li><strong>New AN-X Virtual Analog Engine</strong> - This engine offers a fresh take on virtual analog synthesis, providing more detailed control over sound shaping.</li>
<li><strong>Improved User Interface</strong> - The Montage M features a redesigned user interface with new easy-edit pages and shortcuts, making sound creation and editing more intuitive and efficient.</li>
<li><strong>Additional Knobs and Encoders</strong> - More physical controls give you more immediate access to tweak parameters and add dynamics to your performance.</li>
<li><strong>VCM Rotary Speaker Effect</strong> - This new effect accurately emulates the classic sound of a Leslie speaker cabinet, adding warmth and movement to organ and electric piano sounds.</li>
<li><strong>Powerful USB Audio Interface</strong> - The Montage M functions as a 6-in/32-out USB audio interface, allowing you to record audio directly to your DAW (Digital Audio Workstation) for seamless integration into your studio workflow.</li>
</ul>
<p>The Montage M comes in three versions, each with a different keyboard action</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>M6</strong> - 61-key FSX synth action (ideal for portability and playing melodies).</li>
<li><strong>M7</strong> - 76-key FSX synth action (a good balance between portability and playability for splits and layers).</li>
<li><strong>M8X</strong> - 88-key weighted hammer action with polyphonic aftertouch (perfect for pianists who need a realistic piano feel and expressive control).</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the Yamaha Montage M is a premium synthesizer workstation offering a powerful combination of sound quality, versatile sound engines, improved control options, and seamless studio integration. It caters to professional keyboardists who demand the best in performance and production capabilities.</p>
<h2 id="prices">Prices</h2>
<p>As of June 2024</p>
<ul>
<li>Yamaha Montage M6 (61-key): £3,219 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/yamaha-montage-m6-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
<li>Yamaha Montage M7 (76-key): £3,629 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/yamaha-montage-m7-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
<li>Yamaha Montage M8X (88-key): £4,049 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/yamaha-montage-m8x-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="alternatives">Alternatives</h2>
<p>Here are a few alternative workstation synths to consider</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.korg.com/uk/products/synthesizers/nautilus/">Korg Nautilus</a> (£1,499 - £2,055, as of June 2024)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.roland.com/global/promos/fantom_ex_series/">Roland Fantom EX</a> (£3,599 - £4,177, as of June 2024)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="youtube-videos">YouTube Videos</h2>
<h3 id="mike-patrick-is-blown-away-by-the-new-yamaha-montage-m8x">Mike Patrick is Blown Away by the NEW Yamaha Montage M8X!</h3>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NrISTHXtlfk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h3 id="the-glorious-yamaha-montage-m8x">The glorious Yamaha Montage M8X</h3>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C6BAIrv_gfo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h3 id="yamaha--montage-m-sound-demo">Yamaha | Montage M Sound Demo</h3>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fN59j2cqwoI" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
