<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>fantom on jamesm.blog</title>
    <link>https://jamesm.blog/tags/fantom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fantom on jamesm.blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 22:29:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamesm.blog/tags/fantom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roland Fantom EX</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/roland-fantom-ex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 22:29:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/roland-fantom-ex/</guid>
      <description>About The Roland Fantom EX is a series of professional-grade synthesizer workstations aimed at musicians and producers. It&amp;rsquo;s known for its versatility, high-quality sounds, and powerful features. Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of its key characteristics:
Sounds Diverse sound library with over 7,000 tones covering various musical styles. Roland&amp;rsquo;s sound engine technologies like ACB (Analog Circuit Behavior) for realistic analog sounds, ZEN-Core for sample-based sounds, V-Piano for superior piano tones, and SuperNATURAL for rich and expressive acoustic instruments.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/Roland-Fantom-8-EX.jpg" type="" alt="alt"  /></p>
<h2 id="about">About</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://www.roland.com/us/products/fantom_8_ex/">Roland Fantom EX</a> is a series of professional-grade synthesizer workstations aimed at musicians and producers. It&rsquo;s known for its versatility, high-quality sounds, and powerful features. Here&rsquo;s a breakdown of its key characteristics:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sounds</strong>
<ul>
<li>Diverse sound library with over 7,000 tones covering various musical styles.</li>
<li>Roland&rsquo;s sound engine technologies like ACB (Analog Circuit Behavior) for realistic analog sounds, ZEN-Core for sample-based sounds, V-Piano for superior piano tones, and SuperNATURAL for rich and expressive acoustic instruments.</li>
<li>Access to premium sound content through Roland Cloud for further sonic exploration.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Hardware and User Interface</strong>
<ul>
<li>Comes in three models: Fantom 6 EX, 7 EX, and 8 EX, differing in the number of keys.</li>
<li>User-friendly interface with a combination of buttons, knobs, sliders, and a large, dynamic color touchscreen for intuitive control and sound shaping.</li>
<li>Option to personalize the interface with custom images.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Workflow and Features</strong>
<ul>
<li>Onboard sampling and composition tools for creating and arranging musical ideas.</li>
<li>TR-REC step sequencer for programming drum beats and rhythmic patterns.</li>
<li>Real-time recording with piano roll editing for capturing and editing musical performances.</li>
<li>RGB pads for triggering sounds, samples, and launching clips.</li>
<li>Various effects processors for adding depth and character to sounds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are some additional points to consider</p>
<ul>
<li>The Fantom EX series was released in 2019, building upon the original Fantom platform.</li>
<li>Existing Fantom owners can upgrade their instruments to include the EX features and sounds through the Roland Cloud Fantom EX Upgrade.</li>
<li>There are many online resources available that provide more detailed information and reviews about the Roland Fantom EX, including <a href="https://www.roland.com/global/promos/fantom_ex_series/">Roland&rsquo;s official website</a>, demos on YouTube and reviews from music stores.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the Roland Fantom EX is a powerful and versatile workstation that caters to a wide range of musical needs. Whether you&rsquo;re a producer, keyboardist, or simply a musician looking for a comprehensive instrument for creating and performing music, the Fantom EX is a great option to consider.</p>
<h2 id="models">Models</h2>
<p>Each FANTOM EX model includes the same internal features, panel layout, and connectivity. The only differences are the keyboard configuration, size, and weight.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.roland.com/us/products/fantom_6_ex/">Fantom 6 EX</a> - The most compact FANTOM EX comes equipped with 61 synth-action keys.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.roland.com/us/products/fantom_7_ex/">Fantom 7 EX</a> - Extend your musical range with 76 synth-action keys.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.roland.com/us/products/fantom_8_ex/">Fantom 8 EX</a> - The top-tier FANTOM EX model with 88 hammer-action keys.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="prices">Prices</h2>
<p>(as of June 2024)</p>
<ul>
<li>Fantom 6 EX: £3,599 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/roland-fantom-6-ex-61-key-flagship-synth/">Andertons</a>)</li>
<li>Fantom 7 EX: £3,799 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/roland-fantom-7-ex-72-key-flagship-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
<li>Fantom 8 EX: £4,177 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/roland-fantom-8-ex-88-key-flagship-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="specifications">Specifications</h2>
<ul>
<li>Roland’s premier synthesizer series, updated and enhanced with the latest technologies</li>
<li>Powerful and intuitive user interface designed for free-flowing creativity</li>
<li>Compose and perform with Roland’s most advanced sound engines: ACB, ZEN-Core, V-Piano, SuperNATURAL, Virtual ToneWheel, and more</li>
<li>Over 7000 onboard sounds from the historic Roland library</li>
<li>JUPITER-8, SH-101, and JX-3P ACB Expansions</li>
<li>n/zyme, JD-800, JUNO-106, JUPITER-8, JX-8P, and SH-101 Model Expansions</li>
<li>V-Piano engine with updated UI and preinstalled German Concert V-Piano Expansion 01</li>
<li>SuperNATURAL piano engines and preinstalled SuperNATURAL Acoustic Piano 3 Expansion</li>
<li>Virtual ToneWheel organs derived from the Roland VK series</li>
<li>Massive effects library, including new studio-grade Shimmer Reverb and Modulation Reverb</li>
<li>Master FX processor enhanced with ready-to-use presets and updated UI for Mastering Comp and Mastering EQ</li>
<li>Stereo vocoder with 32 bands</li>
<li>Professional sequencing tools with clip-based workflow, TR-REC step sequencer, piano-roll editing, and more</li>
<li>Advanced sampling with one-shot playback, pitched keyboard assignment, and multisample support</li>
<li>Large color touchscreen and ergonomic panel layout loaded with knobs, buttons, and sliders</li>
<li>16 RGB pads for trigging sounds, samples, and clips</li>
<li>Comprehensive connectivity with multi-channel audio I/O, MIDI I/O, dual CV/gate outputs, USB, and more</li>
<li>16x3 audio/MIDI USB interface</li>
<li>Dedicated software control modes for Ableton Live, Logic Pro, MainStage, Cubase, and Studio One</li>
<li>Expand your creative range with ZEN-Core Sound Packs and Wave Expansions on Roland Cloud</li>
<li>FANTOM EX Upgrade available to original FANTOM owners on Roland Cloud</li>
<li>Premium 76-note keyboard with synth action and channel aftertouch</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="alternatives">Alternatives</h2>
<p>Here are a few alternative workstation synths to consider</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.korg.com/uk/products/synthesizers/nautilus/">Korg Nautilus</a> (£1,499 - £2,055, as of June 2024)</li>
<li><a href="https://uk.yamaha.com/en/products/music_production/synthesizers/montagem/index.html">Yahama Montage M</a> (£3,219 - £4,049, as of June 2024)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="youtube-videos">YouTube Videos</h2>
<h3 id="2024-04-25-roland-fantom-ex-synthesizer--performance-featuring-lzarus">[2024-04-25] Roland FANTOM EX Synthesizer | Performance featuring LZARUS</h3>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qz9b1l7wE5E" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h3 id="2024-11-08-roland-fantom-ex-upgrade-sound-demos">[2024-11-08] Roland FANTOM EX Upgrade Sound Demos</h3>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mVCTwc_m-3s" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h3 id="2024-11-08-roland-fantom-ex-upgrade-josh-blair-interview">[2024-11-08] Roland FANTOM EX Upgrade Josh Blair Interview</h3>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9jrc_x9UFtk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h3 id="2023-11-08-the-roland-fantom-ex-in-action">[2023-11-08] The Roland Fantom EX In Action</h3>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EA3AEoKqeIc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h3 id="2023-11-14-roland-fantom-ex-update---will-it-win-jack-over">[2023-11-14] Roland Fantom EX Update - Will It Win Jack Over?</h3>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/MeBMfO9vTfc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
