<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Synthesizers on jamesm.blog</title>
    <link>https://jamesm.blog/tags/synthesizers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Synthesizers on jamesm.blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:31:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamesm.blog/tags/synthesizers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roland Jupiter‑X Review: A Workstation‑Level Synth with Legendary Sound</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/roland-jupiter-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:31:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/roland-jupiter-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Roland Jupiter‑X&lt;/strong&gt; is one of Roland’s most ambitious synthesizers, combining classic analog-inspired tones with advanced digital synthesis and modern performance features. Designed for musicians, producers, and live performers, it offers the sonic breadth of vintage instruments while providing hands-on control and studio-ready flexibility. As of January 2026 in the UK, the Jupiter‑X typically retails around &lt;strong&gt;£2,155 at Andertons Music Co.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-modern-take-on-a-classic-lineage&#34;&gt;A Modern Take on a Classic Lineage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jupiter‑X isn’t a simple reissue of any single classic synth. Instead, it leverages Roland’s &lt;strong&gt;ZEN-Core synthesis platform&lt;/strong&gt; to model multiple legendary instruments, including the JUPITER‑8, JUNO‑106, SH‑101, and classic drum machine sounds. This makes it a &lt;strong&gt;complete sound studio in a keyboard&lt;/strong&gt;, capable of producing everything from vintage leads and pads to complex layered textures and modern synth sounds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>Roland Jupiter‑X</strong> is one of Roland’s most ambitious synthesizers, combining classic analog-inspired tones with advanced digital synthesis and modern performance features. Designed for musicians, producers, and live performers, it offers the sonic breadth of vintage instruments while providing hands-on control and studio-ready flexibility. As of January 2026 in the UK, the Jupiter‑X typically retails around <strong>£2,155 at Andertons Music Co.</strong></p>
<h2 id="a-modern-take-on-a-classic-lineage">A Modern Take on a Classic Lineage</h2>
<p>The Jupiter‑X isn’t a simple reissue of any single classic synth. Instead, it leverages Roland’s <strong>ZEN-Core synthesis platform</strong> to model multiple legendary instruments, including the JUPITER‑8, JUNO‑106, SH‑101, and classic drum machine sounds. This makes it a <strong>complete sound studio in a keyboard</strong>, capable of producing everything from vintage leads and pads to complex layered textures and modern synth sounds.</p>
<p>Physically, the Jupiter‑X features a solid 61-note semi-weighted keyboard with aftertouch, giving expressive control over filters, effects, and modulation. Its sturdy metal chassis feels at home on both the stage and in the studio.</p>
<h2 id="sound-engine-and-workflow">Sound Engine and Workflow</h2>
<p>At its core, the Jupiter‑X’s ZEN-Core engine allows multiple sound models to run simultaneously. You can create four synth layers plus a dedicated rhythm part, combining analog-style leads, lush pads, drum patterns, and basslines into a single patch.</p>
<p>One standout feature is <strong>I-Arpeggio</strong>, an intelligent arpeggiator that can generate complementary drum patterns, basslines, and chordal movement from your input. This transforms simple melodies into rich musical ideas instantly.</p>
<p>The synth offers direct control through large knobs and sliders, while onboard effects—including delays, reverbs, EQ, and modulation—allow fine-tuning without diving deep into menus. The compact display keeps navigation clear, though advanced patch editing may require some menu work.</p>
<h2 id="strengths-versatility-and-performance">Strengths: Versatility and Performance</h2>
<p>The Jupiter‑X shines for its <strong>sound versatility</strong>. It doesn’t just emulate classic Roland instruments; it lets you <strong>layer them seamlessly</strong>. You can play lush JUPITER‑8 chords under a punchy SH‑101 bassline with a full drum groove, all in real time.</p>
<p>In the <strong>studio</strong>, it serves as an all-in-one instrument, reducing the need for multiple keyboards or plugins. For <strong>live performance</strong>, fast preset and Scene recall, combined with generous polyphony, ensures smooth transitions between vastly different sounds mid-set. USB audio/MIDI, balanced outputs, pedal inputs, and Bluetooth connectivity make integration with DAWs and mobile setups straightforward.</p>
<h2 id="limitations-complexity-and-price">Limitations: Complexity and Price</h2>
<p>This breadth of features comes at a cost—both in terms of price and complexity. At approximately <strong>£2,155</strong> in the UK, the Jupiter‑X sits above entry-level synths and many workstations. Its depth can require menu navigation for advanced patch creation, which may interrupt workflow for some users. While the build is solid, the layout may feel slightly cramped compared to larger workstations with color displays and extensive control surfaces.</p>
<h2 id="who-should-consider-the-jupiterx">Who Should Consider the Jupiter‑X?</h2>
<p>The Jupiter‑X is ideal for <strong>producers and performers</strong> seeking one keyboard that can do it all: classic analog emulations, modern digital textures, rhythm parts, layered patches, and expressive live control. It rewards time and exploration, making it a powerful tool for evolving creative needs.</p>
<p>If your focus is strictly vintage analog sound or ultra-deep sound design without a performance angle, more specialized hardware or software synths might be more cost-effective. However, for a hands-on, versatile powerhouse that bridges the past and the present, the Jupiter‑X stands out as a compelling choice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roland Juno‑X Review: A Modern Reinterpretation of a Classic Synth</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/roland-juno-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 21:42:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/roland-juno-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;roland-junox-review-a-modern-reinterpretation-of-a-classic-synth&#34;&gt;Roland Juno‑X Review: A Modern Reinterpretation of a Classic Synth&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Roland Juno‑X&lt;/strong&gt; is Roland’s contemporary take on one of the most iconic synth lines in history. Designed for musicians and producers who love the classic Juno sound but need modern reliability and flexibility, the Juno‑X blends vintage-inspired tones with hands-on control and studio-ready digital features. As of January 2026 in the UK, the Juno‑X typically retails around &lt;strong&gt;£1,618 at Andertons Music Co.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="roland-junox-review-a-modern-reinterpretation-of-a-classic-synth">Roland Juno‑X Review: A Modern Reinterpretation of a Classic Synth</h1>
<p>The <strong>Roland Juno‑X</strong> is Roland’s contemporary take on one of the most iconic synth lines in history. Designed for musicians and producers who love the classic Juno sound but need modern reliability and flexibility, the Juno‑X blends vintage-inspired tones with hands-on control and studio-ready digital features. As of January 2026 in the UK, the Juno‑X typically retails around <strong>£1,618 at Andertons Music Co.</strong></p>
<h2 id="honoring-the-juno-legacy">Honoring the Juno Legacy</h2>
<p>The original Juno series, including the Juno‑60 and Juno‑106, was celebrated for its <strong>warm, immediate sound</strong> and straightforward interface. Affordable, stable, and musically inspiring, these synths helped define the sound of 1980s synth-pop and electronic music.</p>
<p>The Juno‑X doesn’t attempt to recreate the original analog circuitry. Instead, it captures the <strong>experience and character</strong> of a Juno using Roland’s <strong>ZEN-Core digital synthesis engine</strong>, giving players classic sounds with the advantages of modern polyphony, layering, and effects.</p>
<h2 id="sound-engine-and-workflow">Sound Engine and Workflow</h2>
<p>The Juno‑X features multiple sound models, including faithful recreations of the Juno‑60 and Juno‑106, alongside modern digital tones. Its high polyphony allows for dense pads, layered textures, and complex harmonies—far beyond the six-voice limit of the original Junos.</p>
<p>A highlight is the <strong>famous Juno chorus</strong>, preserved and expanded in the Juno‑X. Combined with delays, reverbs, and modulation effects, it gives classic Juno tones a fresh, versatile edge.</p>
<p>The interface emphasizes <strong>hands-on playability</strong>, with sliders and knobs laid out in a familiar format. Players can shape oscillators, filters, envelopes, and modulation in real time without navigating menus, while deeper editing is available through the built-in screen or optional software.</p>
<h2 id="strengths-immediacy-and-flexibility">Strengths: Immediacy and Flexibility</h2>
<p>The Juno‑X excels in <strong>quick inspiration and tactile control</strong>. Its sliders, chorus, and effects encourage exploration, making it ideal for writing synth leads, pads, basslines, and evolving textures on the fly.</p>
<p>In the <strong>studio</strong>, it serves as a fast, reliable tool for layering sounds, sketching ideas, and integrating with DAWs via USB and MIDI. For <strong>live performance</strong>, preset recall, splits, and layers ensure smooth transitions between patches without interrupting the flow.</p>
<h2 id="limitations-digital-nature-and-scope">Limitations: Digital Nature and Scope</h2>
<p>While the Juno‑X captures the essence of the original Junos, it does not replicate every quirk of aging analog circuitry. Purists may notice the difference in oscillator drift or component behavior. The built-in speakers are suitable for quick sketches but not for critical listening, and deeper programming requires some menu navigation despite the tactile interface.</p>
<p>At around <strong>£1,618</strong>, it sits between entry-level synths and higher-end workstations, offering strong value for hands-on players but requiring a moderate investment.</p>
<h2 id="who-should-consider-the-junox">Who Should Consider the Juno‑X?</h2>
<p>The Juno‑X is perfect for <strong>producers and performers</strong> seeking a playable, versatile polyphonic synth that channels the classic Juno sound while adding modern convenience. Its tactile interface, high polyphony, and effects make it ideal for synth-pop, electronic, ambient, and live performance contexts.</p>
<p>If your focus is purely vintage analog sound or extreme sound design flexibility, software synths or specialized analog hardware may offer more precision. For a <strong>hands-on, modern reinterpretation of a classic</strong>, however, the Juno‑X delivers a compelling balance of nostalgia and innovation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Roland MC-707 as a MIDI Recorder and Brain for the Yamaha MODX</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/using-mc-707-as-midi-brain-for-modx-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 19:35:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/using-mc-707-as-midi-brain-for-modx-m/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Yamaha MODX M and Roland MC-707 make a surprisingly elegant pair when you stop thinking of them as separate instruments and start treating the MC-707 as a &lt;strong&gt;MIDI recorder and playback brain&lt;/strong&gt; for the MODX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this setup, the MODX becomes your hands and sound engine, while the MC-707 becomes the place where performances are captured, edited, looped, and arranged. It’s a simple idea, but it unlocks a very fluid, performance-first workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Yamaha MODX M and Roland MC-707 make a surprisingly elegant pair when you stop thinking of them as separate instruments and start treating the MC-707 as a <strong>MIDI recorder and playback brain</strong> for the MODX.</p>
<p>In this setup, the MODX becomes your hands and sound engine, while the MC-707 becomes the place where performances are captured, edited, looped, and arranged. It’s a simple idea, but it unlocks a very fluid, performance-first workflow.</p>
<h2 id="the-core-concept">The Core Concept</h2>
<p>At its heart, this setup is about <strong>MIDI capture and replay</strong>.</p>
<p>When you play the MODX keyboard, it sends MIDI note data — pitch, timing, velocity, note on and note off. The MC-707 records that data exactly as played. On playback, it sends the same MIDI back to the MODX, which reproduces the performance.</p>
<p>The MC-707 isn’t “understanding” harmony, melody, or intent. It’s acting like a high-quality tape machine for MIDI — precise, repeatable, and editable.</p>
<h2 id="basic-connection">Basic Connection</h2>
<p>The cleanest way to connect the two is with traditional MIDI:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>MODX MIDI OUT → MC-707 MIDI IN</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>USB MIDI can work, but using DIN avoids host/device confusion and is generally more predictable, especially in hardware-only setups.</p>
<h2 id="mc-707-setup">MC-707 Setup</h2>
<p>On the MC-707:</p>
<ul>
<li>Create a <strong>MIDI track</strong> (not a Tone track)</li>
<li>Set the MIDI input channel to match the MODX transmit channel</li>
<li>Arm the track for real-time recording</li>
</ul>
<p>This tells the MC-707 to listen to the MODX and capture whatever you play.</p>
<h2 id="modx-setup">MODX Setup</h2>
<p>On the MODX M:</p>
<ul>
<li>Set the keyboard transmit channel to match the MC-707 MIDI track</li>
<li>Set <strong>Local Control = OFF</strong> if you want to avoid double-triggering during playback</li>
</ul>
<p>With Local Control off, the MODX becomes a controller feeding the MC-707, and the MC-707 becomes the source of all playback MIDI.</p>
<h2 id="recording-a-performance">Recording a Performance</h2>
<p>Recording is straightforward:</p>
<ol>
<li>Press record on the MC-707</li>
<li>Play on the MODX keyboard</li>
<li>Stop recording</li>
</ol>
<p>The MC-707 records:</p>
<ul>
<li>Notes</li>
<li>Timing</li>
<li>Velocity</li>
<li>Performance feel</li>
</ul>
<p>When you press play, the MC-707 sends that MIDI back to the MODX and the performance is recreated exactly.</p>
<p>At this point, the MC-707 is no longer just a groovebox — it’s acting as a central sequencer for an external synth.</p>
<h2 id="editing-and-playback">Editing and Playback</h2>
<p>Once the MIDI is recorded, you can:</p>
<ul>
<li>Loop sections</li>
<li>Apply quantisation (or leave things human)</li>
<li>Duplicate patterns</li>
<li>Build full arrangements across scenes</li>
</ul>
<p>All without touching the MODX keyboard again, unless you want to re-record or layer something new.</p>
<h2 id="working-with-modx-performances-and-arpeggios">Working with MODX Performances and Arpeggios</h2>
<p>If the MODX Performance uses arpeggios or motion sequences, you have two creative options:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Record the keys you play</strong> and let the MODX regenerate movement on playback</li>
<li><strong>Record the generated MIDI output</strong> for total control inside the MC-707</li>
</ul>
<p>Both approaches are valid. One keeps the intelligence inside the MODX, the other commits everything into the MC-707.</p>
<h2 id="multi-part-and-layered-sounds">Multi-Part and Layered Sounds</h2>
<p>The MODX M can transmit on multiple MIDI channels when using layered Performances. The MC-707 can record this, but it’s usually easier to start with a single Part and channel until the workflow feels solid.</p>
<p>Once comfortable, expanding to multiple tracks and channels becomes much more intuitive.</p>
<h2 id="why-this-setup-works-so-well">Why This Setup Works So Well</h2>
<p>This pairing plays to the strengths of both machines:</p>
<ul>
<li>The <strong>MODX M</strong> excels at expressive playing, sound design, and performance control</li>
<li>The <strong>MC-707</strong> excels at capturing, looping, arranging, and recalling musical ideas</li>
</ul>
<p>Instead of programming notes step-by-step, you perform ideas once and let the sequencer handle repetition and structure.</p>
<h2 id="summary">Summary</h2>
<p>Using the Roland MC-707 as a MIDI recorder and playback device for the Yamaha MODX M is simple, reliable, and musically satisfying. It turns the MC-707 into a central brain and the MODX into a powerful performance instrument — a combination that encourages playing first and organising later.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roland Fantom EX</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/roland-fantom-ex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 22:29:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/roland-fantom-ex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://jamesm.blog/images/Roland-Fantom-8-EX.jpg&#34; type=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;alt&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.roland.com/us/products/fantom_8_ex/&#34;&gt;Roland Fantom EX&lt;/a&gt; is a series of professional-grade synthesizer workstations aimed at musicians and producers. It&amp;rsquo;s known for its versatility, high-quality sounds, and powerful features. Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of its key characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sounds&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diverse sound library with over 7,000 tones covering various musical styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roland&amp;rsquo;s sound engine technologies like ACB (Analog Circuit Behavior) for realistic analog sounds, ZEN-Core for sample-based sounds, V-Piano for superior piano tones, and SuperNATURAL for rich and expressive acoustic instruments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to premium sound content through Roland Cloud for further sonic exploration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware and User Interface&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comes in three models: Fantom 6 EX, 7 EX, and 8 EX, differing in the number of keys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User-friendly interface with a combination of buttons, knobs, sliders, and a large, dynamic color touchscreen for intuitive control and sound shaping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Option to personalize the interface with custom images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workflow and Features&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboard sampling and composition tools for creating and arranging musical ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TR-REC step sequencer for programming drum beats and rhythmic patterns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-time recording with piano roll editing for capturing and editing musical performances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RGB pads for triggering sounds, samples, and launching clips.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various effects processors for adding depth and character to sounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional points to consider&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/Roland-Fantom-8-EX.jpg" type="" alt="alt"  /></p>
<h2 id="about">About</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://www.roland.com/us/products/fantom_8_ex/">Roland Fantom EX</a> is a series of professional-grade synthesizer workstations aimed at musicians and producers. It&rsquo;s known for its versatility, high-quality sounds, and powerful features. Here&rsquo;s a breakdown of its key characteristics:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sounds</strong>
<ul>
<li>Diverse sound library with over 7,000 tones covering various musical styles.</li>
<li>Roland&rsquo;s sound engine technologies like ACB (Analog Circuit Behavior) for realistic analog sounds, ZEN-Core for sample-based sounds, V-Piano for superior piano tones, and SuperNATURAL for rich and expressive acoustic instruments.</li>
<li>Access to premium sound content through Roland Cloud for further sonic exploration.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Hardware and User Interface</strong>
<ul>
<li>Comes in three models: Fantom 6 EX, 7 EX, and 8 EX, differing in the number of keys.</li>
<li>User-friendly interface with a combination of buttons, knobs, sliders, and a large, dynamic color touchscreen for intuitive control and sound shaping.</li>
<li>Option to personalize the interface with custom images.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Workflow and Features</strong>
<ul>
<li>Onboard sampling and composition tools for creating and arranging musical ideas.</li>
<li>TR-REC step sequencer for programming drum beats and rhythmic patterns.</li>
<li>Real-time recording with piano roll editing for capturing and editing musical performances.</li>
<li>RGB pads for triggering sounds, samples, and launching clips.</li>
<li>Various effects processors for adding depth and character to sounds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Here are some additional points to consider</p>
<ul>
<li>The Fantom EX series was released in 2019, building upon the original Fantom platform.</li>
<li>Existing Fantom owners can upgrade their instruments to include the EX features and sounds through the Roland Cloud Fantom EX Upgrade.</li>
<li>There are many online resources available that provide more detailed information and reviews about the Roland Fantom EX, including <a href="https://www.roland.com/global/promos/fantom_ex_series/">Roland&rsquo;s official website</a>, demos on YouTube and reviews from music stores.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the Roland Fantom EX is a powerful and versatile workstation that caters to a wide range of musical needs. Whether you&rsquo;re a producer, keyboardist, or simply a musician looking for a comprehensive instrument for creating and performing music, the Fantom EX is a great option to consider.</p>
<h2 id="models">Models</h2>
<p>Each FANTOM EX model includes the same internal features, panel layout, and connectivity. The only differences are the keyboard configuration, size, and weight.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.roland.com/us/products/fantom_6_ex/">Fantom 6 EX</a> - The most compact FANTOM EX comes equipped with 61 synth-action keys.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.roland.com/us/products/fantom_7_ex/">Fantom 7 EX</a> - Extend your musical range with 76 synth-action keys.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.roland.com/us/products/fantom_8_ex/">Fantom 8 EX</a> - The top-tier FANTOM EX model with 88 hammer-action keys.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="prices">Prices</h2>
<p>(as of June 2024)</p>
<ul>
<li>Fantom 6 EX: £3,599 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/roland-fantom-6-ex-61-key-flagship-synth/">Andertons</a>)</li>
<li>Fantom 7 EX: £3,799 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/roland-fantom-7-ex-72-key-flagship-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
<li>Fantom 8 EX: £4,177 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/roland-fantom-8-ex-88-key-flagship-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="specifications">Specifications</h2>
<ul>
<li>Roland’s premier synthesizer series, updated and enhanced with the latest technologies</li>
<li>Powerful and intuitive user interface designed for free-flowing creativity</li>
<li>Compose and perform with Roland’s most advanced sound engines: ACB, ZEN-Core, V-Piano, SuperNATURAL, Virtual ToneWheel, and more</li>
<li>Over 7000 onboard sounds from the historic Roland library</li>
<li>JUPITER-8, SH-101, and JX-3P ACB Expansions</li>
<li>n/zyme, JD-800, JUNO-106, JUPITER-8, JX-8P, and SH-101 Model Expansions</li>
<li>V-Piano engine with updated UI and preinstalled German Concert V-Piano Expansion 01</li>
<li>SuperNATURAL piano engines and preinstalled SuperNATURAL Acoustic Piano 3 Expansion</li>
<li>Virtual ToneWheel organs derived from the Roland VK series</li>
<li>Massive effects library, including new studio-grade Shimmer Reverb and Modulation Reverb</li>
<li>Master FX processor enhanced with ready-to-use presets and updated UI for Mastering Comp and Mastering EQ</li>
<li>Stereo vocoder with 32 bands</li>
<li>Professional sequencing tools with clip-based workflow, TR-REC step sequencer, piano-roll editing, and more</li>
<li>Advanced sampling with one-shot playback, pitched keyboard assignment, and multisample support</li>
<li>Large color touchscreen and ergonomic panel layout loaded with knobs, buttons, and sliders</li>
<li>16 RGB pads for trigging sounds, samples, and clips</li>
<li>Comprehensive connectivity with multi-channel audio I/O, MIDI I/O, dual CV/gate outputs, USB, and more</li>
<li>16x3 audio/MIDI USB interface</li>
<li>Dedicated software control modes for Ableton Live, Logic Pro, MainStage, Cubase, and Studio One</li>
<li>Expand your creative range with ZEN-Core Sound Packs and Wave Expansions on Roland Cloud</li>
<li>FANTOM EX Upgrade available to original FANTOM owners on Roland Cloud</li>
<li>Premium 76-note keyboard with synth action and channel aftertouch</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="alternatives">Alternatives</h2>
<p>Here are a few alternative workstation synths to consider</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.korg.com/uk/products/synthesizers/nautilus/">Korg Nautilus</a> (£1,499 - £2,055, as of June 2024)</li>
<li><a href="https://uk.yamaha.com/en/products/music_production/synthesizers/montagem/index.html">Yahama Montage M</a> (£3,219 - £4,049, as of June 2024)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="youtube-videos">YouTube Videos</h2>
<h3 id="2024-04-25-roland-fantom-ex-synthesizer--performance-featuring-lzarus">[2024-04-25] Roland FANTOM EX Synthesizer | Performance featuring LZARUS</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qz9b1l7wE5E?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h3 id="2024-11-08-roland-fantom-ex-upgrade-sound-demos">[2024-11-08] Roland FANTOM EX Upgrade Sound Demos</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/mVCTwc_m-3s?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h3 id="2024-11-08-roland-fantom-ex-upgrade-josh-blair-interview">[2024-11-08] Roland FANTOM EX Upgrade Josh Blair Interview</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/9jrc_x9UFtk?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h3 id="2023-11-08-the-roland-fantom-ex-in-action">[2023-11-08] The Roland Fantom EX In Action</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EA3AEoKqeIc?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h3 id="2023-11-14-roland-fantom-ex-update---will-it-win-jack-over">[2023-11-14] Roland Fantom EX Update - Will It Win Jack Over?</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/MeBMfO9vTfc?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yamaha Montage M</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/yamaha-montage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 08:29:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/music-production/yamaha-montage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://jamesm.blog/images/Yamaha-Montage-M.jpg&#34; type=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;alt&#34;  /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://uk.yamaha.com/en/products/music_production/synthesizers/montagem/index.html&#34;&gt;Yamaha Montage M&lt;/a&gt; was released in the UK on 10th October 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the next-generation &lt;strong&gt;flagship synthesizer&lt;/strong&gt; from Yamaha, building on the success of the original Montage. It boasts several improvements and new features designed to enhance the sound, control, and workflow for professional keyboardists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a summary of the key aspects of the Yamaha Montage M&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three Powerful Engines&lt;/strong&gt; -  Like its predecessor, Montage M features three sound engines: AN-X, AWM2, and FM-X. These engines offer a vast sonic palette, allowing you to create warm vintage analog tones, cutting-edge FM sounds, and ultra-realistic acoustic instruments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased Polyphony&lt;/strong&gt; - A significant upgrade is the 400-note total polyphony, a jump from the original Montage&amp;rsquo;s 256 notes. This allows for more complex and layered sounds without worrying about dropped notes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New AN-X Virtual Analog Engine&lt;/strong&gt; - This engine offers a fresh take on virtual analog synthesis, providing more detailed control over sound shaping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved User Interface&lt;/strong&gt; - The Montage M features a redesigned user interface with new easy-edit pages and shortcuts, making sound creation and editing more intuitive and efficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Knobs and Encoders&lt;/strong&gt; - More physical controls give you more immediate access to tweak parameters and add dynamics to your performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VCM Rotary Speaker Effect&lt;/strong&gt; - This new effect accurately emulates the classic sound of a Leslie speaker cabinet, adding warmth and movement to organ and electric piano sounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Powerful USB Audio Interface&lt;/strong&gt; - The Montage M functions as a 6-in/32-out USB audio interface, allowing you to record audio directly to your DAW (Digital Audio Workstation) for seamless integration into your studio workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Yamaha Montage M is a premium synthesizer workstation offering a powerful combination of sound quality, versatile sound engines, improved control options, and seamless studio integration. It caters to professional keyboardists who demand the best in performance and production capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/Yamaha-Montage-M.jpg" type="" alt="alt"  /></p>
<h2 id="about">About</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://uk.yamaha.com/en/products/music_production/synthesizers/montagem/index.html">Yamaha Montage M</a> was released in the UK on 10th October 2023.</p>
<p>It is the next-generation <strong>flagship synthesizer</strong> from Yamaha, building on the success of the original Montage. It boasts several improvements and new features designed to enhance the sound, control, and workflow for professional keyboardists.</p>
<p>Here is a summary of the key aspects of the Yamaha Montage M</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Three Powerful Engines</strong> -  Like its predecessor, Montage M features three sound engines: AN-X, AWM2, and FM-X. These engines offer a vast sonic palette, allowing you to create warm vintage analog tones, cutting-edge FM sounds, and ultra-realistic acoustic instruments.</li>
<li><strong>Increased Polyphony</strong> - A significant upgrade is the 400-note total polyphony, a jump from the original Montage&rsquo;s 256 notes. This allows for more complex and layered sounds without worrying about dropped notes.</li>
<li><strong>New AN-X Virtual Analog Engine</strong> - This engine offers a fresh take on virtual analog synthesis, providing more detailed control over sound shaping.</li>
<li><strong>Improved User Interface</strong> - The Montage M features a redesigned user interface with new easy-edit pages and shortcuts, making sound creation and editing more intuitive and efficient.</li>
<li><strong>Additional Knobs and Encoders</strong> - More physical controls give you more immediate access to tweak parameters and add dynamics to your performance.</li>
<li><strong>VCM Rotary Speaker Effect</strong> - This new effect accurately emulates the classic sound of a Leslie speaker cabinet, adding warmth and movement to organ and electric piano sounds.</li>
<li><strong>Powerful USB Audio Interface</strong> - The Montage M functions as a 6-in/32-out USB audio interface, allowing you to record audio directly to your DAW (Digital Audio Workstation) for seamless integration into your studio workflow.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, the Yamaha Montage M is a premium synthesizer workstation offering a powerful combination of sound quality, versatile sound engines, improved control options, and seamless studio integration. It caters to professional keyboardists who demand the best in performance and production capabilities.</p>
<h2 id="models">Models</h2>
<p>The Montage M comes in three versions, each with a different keyboard action</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>M6</strong> - 61-key FSX synth action (ideal for portability and playing melodies).</li>
<li><strong>M7</strong> - 76-key FSX synth action (a good balance between portability and playability for splits and layers).</li>
<li><strong>M8X</strong> - 88-key weighted hammer action with polyphonic aftertouch (perfect for pianists who need a realistic piano feel and expressive control).</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="prices">Prices</h2>
<p>(as of June 2024)</p>
<ul>
<li>Montage M6 (61-key): £3,219 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/yamaha-montage-m6-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
<li>Montage M7 (76-key): £3,629 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/yamaha-montage-m7-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
<li>Montage M8X (88-key): £4,049 (<a href="https://www.andertons.co.uk/yamaha-montage-m8x-synthesizer/">Andertons</a>)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="specifications">Specifications</h2>
<ul>
<li>Tone Generators: AWM2</li>
<li>2 X 128 Voices of Polyphony (128 Voices Each for Preset and User Waveforms) Max. 128 Elements Per Part</li>
<li>10 GB Preset Waveforms (When Converted In 16 Bit Linear)</li>
<li>7 GB Flash Memory for User Waveforms</li>
<li>FM-X - 128 Voices of Polyphony, 8 Operators, 88 Algorithms</li>
<li>AN-X - 16 Voices of Polyphony, 3 Oscillators, 1 Noise Generator</li>
<li>3,369 Preset Performances</li>
<li>128 Preset Live Sets, 2,048 User Live Sets</li>
<li>Motion Sequencer for Real-Time Control of Parameters</li>
<li>16 Part Multitimbrality Plus Audio Input Parts (A/D In, USB)</li>
<li>18 Filter Types</li>
<li>5-Band Master-EQ, 2 Part-EQs (3- And 2-Band)</li>
<li>Sequencer 16 Tracks, 128 Patterns, 128 Songs</li>
<li>Arpeggiator: Arpeggios for Up to Eight Parts In Parallel</li>
<li>10,922 Preset Arpeggios (3,500 Rhythm Patterns), 256 User Arpeggios</li>
<li>Controllers: Pitch Bend and Modulation Wheel</li>
<li>Polyphonic aftertouch</li>
<li>Ribbon Controller - 8 Control Sliders, 8 Assignable Knobs, Super Knob</li>
<li>2 Assignable Switches</li>
<li>Portamento Switch and Portamento Time Knob, 6 Display Knobs</li>
<li>Displays Main: 7” TFT Colour Wide VGA LCD Touch Screen</li>
<li>Sub: 512 X 64 Pixel LCD</li>
<li>Connectors: OUTPUT [L MONO]/[R], ASSIGNABLE OUTPUT [L]/[R]</li>
<li>A/D INPUT [L MONO]/[R] (All 6.3 Mm TRS Jacks)</li>
<li>Phones: Stereo (6.3mm Phone Jack)</li>
<li>Midi In/Out/Thru</li>
<li>Foot Controller 1 / 2</li>
<li>Foot Switch Sustain / Assignable</li>
<li>2 X Usb to Device, USB To Host</li>
<li>6 Channels Input, 32 Channels Output At 44.1 Khz</li>
<li>6 Channels Input, 8 Channels Output At 192 Khz</li>
<li>Dimensions: (W X D X H) / Weight:</li>
<li>M8X: 1,446 Mm × 460 Mm × 170 Mm / 28.1 Kg</li>
<li>Included Accessories: Owner’s Manual, AC Power Cord, Cubase AI Download</li>
<li>Compatible Accessories: Foot Switches and Controllers (FC3A, FC4A, FC5, FC7)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="alternatives">Alternatives</h2>
<p>Here are a few alternative workstation synths to consider</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.korg.com/uk/products/synthesizers/nautilus/">Korg Nautilus</a> (£1,499 - £2,055, as of June 2024)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.roland.com/global/promos/fantom_ex_series/">Roland Fantom EX</a> (£3,599 - £4,177, as of June 2024)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="youtube-videos">YouTube Videos</h2>
<h3 id="2024-01-26-the-glorious-yamaha-montage-m8x">[2024-01-26] The glorious Yamaha Montage M8X</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/C6BAIrv_gfo?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h3 id="2024-01-06-yamaha-montage-m8x-acoustic-pianos-demo">[2024-01-06] Yamaha Montage M8X Acoustic Pianos Demo</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XCS3c6_f1Ow?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h3 id="2023-10-19-yamaha-montage-m8x-synthesizerworkstation-sound-test">[2023-10-19] Yamaha Montage M8X Synthesizer/Workstation sound test</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/6WfJOqS1HPw?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h3 id="2023-10-11-mike-patrick-is-blown-away-by-the-new-yamaha-montage-m8x">[2023-10-11] Mike Patrick is Blown Away by the NEW Yamaha Montage M8X!</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/NrISTHXtlfk?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h3 id="2023-10-11-yamaha-montage-m8x---their-flagship-synth-is-more-powerful-than-ever">[2023-10-11] Yamaha Montage M8x - Their Flagship Synth Is More Powerful Than Ever!</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/z-4M8DegHRQ?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h3 id="2023-10-10-yamaha--montage-m-sound-demo">[2023-10-10] Yamaha | Montage M Sound Demo</h3>
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/fN59j2cqwoI?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
