<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>github on jamesm.blog</title>
    <link>https://jamesm.blog/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in github on jamesm.blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 06:45:18 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamesm.blog/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>List of DevOps GitHub Projects</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/devops/github-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 06:45:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/devops/github-projects/</guid>
      <description>DevOps &amp;amp; Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) Awesome Scalability - reading list for illustrating the patterns of scalable, reliable, and performant large-scale systems Awesome Site Reliability Engineering - curated list of awesome Site Reliability and Production Engineering resources DevOps Exercises - contains questions and exercises on technical topics related to DevOps and SRE How they SRE - curated collection of publicly available resources about SRE Kubernetes k9s - terminal UI to interact with your Kubernetes clusters kOps - Kubernetes operations kube-state-metrics (KSM) - simple service that listens to the Kubernetes API server and generates metrics about the state of the objects Kubernetes Dashboard - general purpose, web-based UI for Kubernetes clusters Kubespray - Kubernetes cluster lifecycle management minikube - implements a local Kubernetes cluster on macOS, Linux, and Windows for you to practice and learn Popeye - scans a live Kubernetes cluster and reports potential issues with deployed resources and configurations Linux bat - a cat clone with syntax highlighting and Git integration pueue - command-line task management tool for sequential and parallel execution of long-running tasks specctl - command-line based tool to extract and transform Kubernetes objects to ECS and vice versa Test your SysAdmin skills - interview questions and answers for system administration Scheduling Airflow - platform to programmatically author, schedule, and monitor workflows dkron - distributed, fault tolerant job scheduling system for cloud native environments </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="devops--site-reliability-engineering-sre">DevOps &amp; Site Reliability Engineering (SRE)</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/binhnguyennus/awesome-scalability/">Awesome Scalability</a> - reading list for illustrating the patterns of scalable, reliable, and performant large-scale systems</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/dastergon/awesome-sre/">Awesome Site Reliability Engineering</a> - curated list of awesome Site Reliability and Production Engineering resources</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/bregman-arie/devops-exercises/">DevOps Exercises</a> - contains questions and exercises on technical topics related to DevOps and SRE</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/upgundecha/howtheysre/">How they SRE</a> - curated collection of publicly available resources about SRE</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="kubernetes">Kubernetes</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/derailed/k9s/">k9s</a> - terminal UI to interact with your Kubernetes clusters</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kops/">kOps</a> - Kubernetes operations</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kube-state-metrics/">kube-state-metrics (KSM)</a> - simple service that listens to the Kubernetes API server and generates metrics about the state of the objects</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/dashboard/">Kubernetes Dashboard</a> - general purpose, web-based UI for Kubernetes clusters</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes-sigs/kubespray/">Kubespray</a> - Kubernetes cluster lifecycle management</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/minikube/">minikube</a> - implements a local Kubernetes cluster on macOS, Linux, and Windows for you to practice and learn</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/derailed/popeye/">Popeye</a> - scans a live Kubernetes cluster and reports potential issues with deployed resources and configurations</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="linux">Linux</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/sharkdp/bat/">bat</a> - a cat clone with syntax highlighting and Git integration</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Nukesor/pueue/">pueue</a> - command-line task management tool for sequential and parallel execution of long-running tasks</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/awslabs/specctl/">specctl</a> - command-line based tool to extract and transform Kubernetes objects to ECS and vice versa</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/trimstray/test-your-sysadmin-skills/">Test your SysAdmin skills</a> - interview questions and answers for system administration</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="scheduling">Scheduling</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/apache/airflow/">Airflow</a> - platform to programmatically author, schedule, and monitor workflows</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/distribworks/dkron/">dkron</a> - distributed, fault tolerant job scheduling system for cloud native environments</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of AI GitHub Projects</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/ai/github-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 08:01:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/ai/github-projects/</guid>
      <description>Chatbots Auto-GPT - autonomous GPT Dev-GPT - your automated development team Prompt Engineering Guide - latest papers, learning guides, lectures, references &amp;amp; tools related for prompt engineering Other Twitter&amp;rsquo;s Recommendation Algorithm - a set of services and jobs that are responsible for serving feeds of Tweets and other content across all Twitter product surfaces (e.g. For You Timeline, Search, Explore) </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="chatbots">Chatbots</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/Significant-Gravitas/Auto-GPT">Auto-GPT</a> - autonomous GPT</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/jina-ai/dev-gpt">Dev-GPT</a> - your automated development team</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/dair-ai/Prompt-Engineering-Guide">Prompt Engineering Guide</a> - latest papers, learning guides, lectures, references &amp; tools related for prompt engineering</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="other">Other</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/twitter/the-algorithm">Twitter&rsquo;s Recommendation Algorithm</a> - a set of services and jobs that are responsible for serving feeds of Tweets and other content across all Twitter product surfaces (e.g. For You Timeline, Search, Explore)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/ai/github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 11:51:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/ai/github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>GitHub Copilot is a cloud-based artificial intelligence tool developed by GitHub and OpenAI to assist users of Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Neovim, and JetBrains integrated development environments by autocompleting code.
GitHub Copilot uses the OpenAI Codex to suggest code and entire functions in real-time, right from your editor.
Focus on more satisfying work, be more producttive, speed up repetitve tasks.
Supported IDEs
Neovim JetBrains IDEs Visual Studio Visual Studio Code Price: $10 / month</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/features/copilot">GitHub Copilot</a> is a cloud-based artificial intelligence tool developed by GitHub and OpenAI to assist users of Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Neovim, and JetBrains integrated development environments by autocompleting code.</p>
<p>GitHub Copilot uses the OpenAI Codex to suggest code and entire functions in real-time, right from your editor.</p>
<p>Focus on more satisfying work, be more producttive, speed up repetitve tasks.</p>
<p>Supported IDEs</p>
<ul>
<li>Neovim</li>
<li>JetBrains IDEs</li>
<li>Visual Studio</li>
<li>Visual Studio Code</li>
</ul>
<p>Price: $10 / month</p>
<p>Links</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.github.com/en/copilot">Documentation</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
