<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>health data on jamesm.blog</title>
    <link>https://jamesm.blog/tags/health-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health data on jamesm.blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 21:02:39 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jamesm.blog/tags/health-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Health Data</title>
      <link>https://jamesm.blog/personal-development/tracking-health-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 21:02:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesm.blog/personal-development/tracking-health-data/</guid>
      <description>Apps (iOS) Apple Health Megafit-Health Fitness Tool Measures &amp;amp; tracks the following weight, Body Mass Index (BMI), body fat %, body fat weight, body water, bone mass, rate of subcutaneous fat, visceral fat levels, basal metabolism body age, muscle mass &amp;amp; resting calorie consumption data Requires a smart scale Syncs to Apple Health app Zordai Syncs to Apple Health app Smart Watches &amp;hellip; Smart Scales Mpow Bluetooth Weighing Scales I purchased this in 2019, may not be available anymore Syncs with: Apple Health, Fitbit, Google Fit Measures &amp;amp; tracks the following weight, Body Mass Index (BMI), body fat, fat-free body weight, subcutaneous fat, visceral fat, body water, skeletal muscle, muscle mass, bone mass, protein, BMR &amp;amp; metabolic age Other Thriva Understand your internal health, stay ahead of chronic diseases, and extend your healthspan with home blood tests and actionable next steps.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="apps-ios">Apps (iOS)</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/apple-health/id1242545199">Apple Health</a></li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/megafit-health-fitness-tool/id1397720108">Megafit-Health Fitness Tool</a>
<ul>
<li>Measures &amp; tracks the following
<ul>
<li>weight, Body Mass Index (BMI), body fat %, body fat weight, body water, bone mass, rate of subcutaneous fat, visceral fat levels, basal metabolism body age, muscle mass &amp; resting calorie consumption data</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Requires a smart scale</li>
<li>Syncs to Apple Health app</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/zordai/id1635093895">Zordai</a>
<ul>
<li>Syncs to Apple Health app</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="smart-watches">Smart Watches</h2>
<ul>
<li>&hellip;</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="smart-scales">Smart Scales</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.desertcart.com.om/products/150036835-smart-scales-mpow-bluetooth-weighing-scales-body-fat-scales-digital-bmi-bathroom-scales-precision-body-composition-analyzer-for-13-physical-body-data-weight-bmi-muscle-etc-by-app-for-fitness-tracking">Mpow Bluetooth Weighing Scales</a>
<ul>
<li>I purchased this in 2019, may not be available anymore</li>
<li>Syncs with: Apple Health, Fitbit, Google Fit</li>
<li>Measures &amp; tracks the following
<ul>
<li>weight, Body Mass Index (BMI), body fat, fat-free body weight, subcutaneous fat, visceral fat, body water, skeletal muscle, muscle mass, bone mass, protein, BMR &amp; metabolic age</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="other">Other</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://thriva.co/">Thriva</a>
<ul>
<li>Understand your internal health, stay ahead of chronic diseases, and extend your healthspan with home blood tests and actionable next steps.
<ul>
<li>Cholesterol (lipid profile), creatinine, cRP, ferritin, folate, free testosterone, hbA1c (diabetes), liver blood test, omega 3 &amp; 6, total testosterone, vitamin B12 (active), vitamin B12 (total), vitamin B9 &amp; B12 (active), vitamin D</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Note: These at-home blood tests are not a substitute for professional medical care.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
